

☐ +1 551-263-9462 • ☑ yzhang31@wpi.edu

## **Summary**

Ph.D. candidate in Data Science, with strong deep learning background and programming skills and the ability to work independently or as part of a research team. Broad research interests include:

o deep learning

o meta-learning

o reinforcement learning

o imitation Learning

o spatial-temporal data mining

o big data analysis

### Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI) *Ph.D. Candidate in Data Science. GPA 4.0/4.0* Stevens Institute of Technology

M.S in Financial Engineering (Data Science Track). GPA 3.98/4.0

**Shanghai Jiao Tong University** *B.E in Computer Science* 

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China 2012-2016

Worcester, MA Expected 2022

Hoboken, NJ

2016-2018

## Research & Work Experience

### Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Laboratory of Prof. Yanhua Li

Research Assistant

Funded by National Science Foundation

Worcester, MA Aug 2018-Present

- Combined the meta reinforcement learning with meta imitation learning to enable learning of new behaviours (in progress).
- Proposed a Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning algorithm (cST-ML) which employed variational inference and deep neural networks to better capture the temporal uncertainties of time series data.
- o Proposed a novel generative adversarial networks equipped with dynamic convolutional layer and self-attention mechanism to solve the spatial-temporal estimation problem.
- Designed a novel generative adversarial networks to better capture the spatial patterns of spatial-temporal data.

### Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Data Science Research Group

Research Member

Worcester, MA Aug 2018-Present

- Supervised research projects of graduate students on human mobility estimation with conditional generative adversarial networks.
- Assisted other research members in solving research issues related to deep learning and large-scale data analytics.

#### **Stevens Institute of Technology**

Hoboken, NJ

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2017-May 2018

o Assisted in teaching graduate courses including Data Mining and Database Management.

### **Technical Skills**

- **Programming:** Python, R, C/C++, Java
- o Frameworks: PyTorch, TensorFlow, scikit-learn, NumPy, SciPy
- Others: LATEX, Matlab, SQL

#### **Publications**

- [KDD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20).
- o [ICDM] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. TrafficGAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).

- [TBD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation
   A Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks Approach. In IEEE Transactions on Big Data.
- o [Under Submission] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics Prediction.
- o [Under Submission] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 Pandemic through Spatio-Temporal Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks.

# **Conference & Presentation Experience**

26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20) Conference Presentor	Virtual Event Expected Aug 2020
2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) Conference Presentor	Beijing, China Nov 2019
Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE) Poster Presentor	Worcester, MA Feb 2019

Awards

Graduate Fellowship by National Science Foundation

2018-Present
Scholarship for international students from Stevens Institute of Technology

2016-2018